MARK BLOCKER: Okay, in this segment I'm going to cover installing the brake pads.
What I've done is I've laid out the four brake pads that come in a brake pad replacement kit.
You've got two pads for each side of the vehicle.
As you've noticed, there is the difference in two of the pads.
Two pads are identical.
That's the outboard pad on each side and the two inboard pads are inverted so that the warning tab is located in correct position.
So if you take the brake pads, you just remove and match them up.
These two matched.
This is my inboard one.
Both outboard pads are identical for sides so just select one, now I have my 2 pads.
We have to install the silencers that came on the used ones, I'm transferring on to the new ones because it didn't come equip with those.
And you remember there is two distinctively different style silencers used.
The outboard pad had the wide fingers of the outer side of caliper for sealing so I used the wide finger.
Do you to see where it is sealed on before, that's the outboard pad that applies just to that.
This is the inboard pad where the piston applies pressure against the brake pad and that's done in the center.
Now, you want these tabs to be securely mounted, the way to do so is you take a large pair of channel lock pliers and you just adjust them for comfortable grip across the pad and you just squeeze on.
There's two tabs on one side, one in the center, just squeeze and lock those down all three tabs, and that secures the brake silencer to the pad.
And just as safe as you do again with the other brake pad, and it's secure.
Now, we can install the pads into the caliper mounting bracket.
Prior to doing so, where the pads slide back and forth in the caliper assemblies, we want to make sure and lubricate that area.
We want to use a very small amount of lubricant because we don't want an excess to get on the pads or around in the brake system, just adequate to lubricate the system.
Please watch our next segment and we'll cover installing the pads part 2.